<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog</id>
    <title>My UI Portfolio Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog"/>
    <subtitle>My UI Portfolio Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colors 2]]></title>
        <id>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</id>
        <link href="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog"/>
        <updated>2024-09-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Psychology of Color Through Television]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Psychology of Color Through Television</p>
<p>These sections dive into the psychology of color from the feelings each hue in the rainbow invoke to the lucrative market of understanding color trends for different customer segments. One of the most beautiful ways the psychology of color manifests is through film and television. This also is a very intuitive way to understand color theory and the impact of color as our brain subconsciously reacts to the creators choices. One of the best ways in our generation this was demonstrated was in the HBO series Euphoria. Each character has very deliberate colors that make up their wardrobe and this even changes as characters develop and transition. Maddie is a strong, independent, hard to read and confident character which is perfectly exemplified through her palette of rich purples. As purple is the color of royalty is also reflects her desire for upward social mobility. Cassie is often adorned in baby blues which mirror her highly sensitive, emotional personality. It also reflects her character traits of being a people pleaser and impulsive and to be on the nose the sadness and grief that surrounds her character. Kat's whole character arc is about developing confidence in herself and her body as a plus size women. This is beautifully demonstrated as she starts wearing the bold, dominating, and eye catching colors of red and black.</p>]]></content>
        <category label="FreeForm" term="FreeForm"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aesthetic Design]]></title>
        <id>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</id>
        <link href="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post"/>
        <updated>2024-09-20T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds</p>
<p>The rule of thirds was a very important section of this reading . The rule of thirds is derived from another concept called "the golden ratio", which means we are drawn to images that have proportions following the golden ratio which for rectangles has the proportions of 1:1.618. The rule of thirds acts is a technique that all starts with superimposing a 3x3 grid onto the piece in question. The corners of the middle square are the "power points" which are the ideal areas to place your power points. This is a personal tangent but I thought for the longest time the rule of thirds meant that when you are adding the same design elements it is best to do it in groups of three for the most balance. My mom taught me this when she would create bouquets and it is a principle I always think about when creating artwork. I am curious if this abstraction of the official rule of thirds rule has any basis because it always felt like something that elevated my designs. Now I will paste some art pieces I have created and see how well they follow the rule of thirds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Aesthetic Design Analysis" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/aesthetic-design-analysis-bb44c1c1e4346a11fedc786526ae1135.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <category label="FreeForm" term="FreeForm"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Example Blog Post]]></title>
        <id>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</id>
        <link href="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <category label="FreeForm" term="FreeForm"/>
    </entry>
</feed>