<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>My UI Portfolio Blog</title>
        <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog</link>
        <description>My UI Portfolio Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inclusive Design Constraints]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/inclusive-design-constraints</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/inclusive-design-constraints</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Constraints Concept Map]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Constraints Concept Map
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="constraints concept map" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/constraints-c437a279b489419df08051debf21d715.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I decided to map out the four types of constraints detailed in chapter 4 of
"The Design of Everday Things". These tie deeply into the concepts of signifiers
and affordances and are at the corner stone of guiding users easily on how to
use and navigate sites and designs they have no concept of in the past. These
constraints are vital to remember and leverage to faciliate a user experience that builds upon users existing knowledge base.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ConceptMap</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inclusive Design]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/inclusive-design-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/inclusive-design-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Inclusive Design Accessibility]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inclusive Design Accessibility</p>
<p>"Accessibility is to UI/UX design as a ramp is to a sidewalk"</p>
<p>One of the core arguments supporting the need for accesibility is that while it isn't just
the moral thing to do, it also benefits and uplifts all users of the web. Innovations like
closed captioning, larger text, readable and digestible pages, easy accesss to the main
content of a webpage, etc. all serve to empower the user experience on the web. While they are
primarily tabled with individuals from a range of disabilities, many people can benefit
and use these options without a thought to make their web surfing more smooth. This ties into the
analogy, as a lot of things we observe in our day to day that aim to help people with disabilities
also create ease in the places they're implemented in. A sidewalk ramp is vital to those in wheelchairs
and also serves as a net positive for those riding in a bike, parents with strollers, and even just those
feeling a little tired after a long walk!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ApproximateAnalogy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[User Testing Blog]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/user-testing</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/user-testing</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Do It Yourself Testing]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do It Yourself Testing</p>
<p>In today's blog entry I will be capturing the most important pieces in Chapter 9
of Steven Krug's book revered design book "Don't Make Me Think". This chapter
expands on the key component of the desing life cycle: user testing. However Krug offers
a novel, cheaper, and more efficient approach to this practice through "Do It Yourself
Testing".</p>
<ol>
<li>Time Spent For Each Round of Testing</li>
</ol>
<p>One morning per month, this factors in conducting the tests, debriefing, and narrowing
down what fixes to tackle.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>When do you test</li>
</ol>
<p>Throughout the development process rather than when the project is almost done.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Number of testing rounds</li>
</ol>
<p>One per month is all that is nessecary as it it becomes a monthly routine!</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Number of participants</li>
</ol>
<p>3 is more than enough to capture the most vital details</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>How do you choose particpants</li>
</ol>
<p>It is okay to not have the most segmented population to test. The frequency matters
more than the testers profile. It also is good to have prodcts as accessible as possible.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Where do you test</li>
</ol>
<p>On site or remote with observers in a seperate room using screen sharing to analyze.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>Who should watch</li>
</ol>
<p>On site testing allows a wife variety of people working on the project to observe as well
as making it half a day only.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>Reporting</li>
</ol>
<p>1-2 page email is enough to capture the team's decisions during debriefing.</p>
<ol start="9">
<li>Who identifies issues?</li>
</ol>
<p>The development team should contribute to this role as well as key stakeholders who
ideally could meet over lunch to compare and contrast observations.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li>Primary Purpose</li>
</ol>
<p>Identify most common and fatal issues and commit to cleaning those up by the next
month for scheduled testing.</p>
<ol start="11">
<li>Costs</li>
</ol>
<p>A couple hundred dollars or less per round of testing!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Tutorial</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[User Testing 101]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/user-testing-101</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/user-testing-101</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[User Testing 101]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>User Testing 101</p>
<p>"WHY"</p>
<p>In chapter 5 of “Design of Everyday Things” Norman hones in on the devastation that poor design can create and as a result why it is key to be able to diagnose these problems before and as they come about. This leads to the word “why” and how this centers around this main issue Norman brings up. Root cause analysis is centered on the idea how determining what caused an error in someone’s actions. This is where the word “Why” comes into play as often when one wrong move is found the case is closed. This doesn’t account for the possibility of a butterfly effect of multiple decisions causing the issue and also emphasize the human error component to drastically. This is where the “Five Why’s” come into play. The 5 why’s is a Japanese concept developed by Sakichi Toyoda for the Toyota Production System division of the Toyota Motor Company. When searching for this root cause, keep asking “Why” and drill down as deep as possible to exhaust and flesh out the reason for a problematic behavior. The benefits and value of this method is the critical thinking facilitated in this process and pushing back against the tendency to stop finding potential errors once a human error is discovered. This has found mainstream use around a multitude of industries from business executives, UI designer, engineers and so much more.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>WordJournal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mockups Reading]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/mockups-reading-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/mockups-reading-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Big Picture in Planning]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Big Picture in Planning</p>
<p>"Seeing the big picture when creating mockups is to focusing the lens on a camera"</p>
<p>Chapter 2 of Presentation Zen hones in on the importance of drilling down to the big
picture of your design when in the planning stage. Some words of advice outlined in the book
is really sitting by yourself to reach that ideal big picture. It is important to have a clear, undistracted
mind to reach this state where problems and goals that may hinder this process appear. Another
key piece of advice is going "analog" and relying on pens, whiteboards, and papers for rough ideation
to further build the main idea of the design. This immediatly reminded me of the process of zooming
in when taking a picture using a camera. From the visual experience being the photographer to the actual
mechanics the camera goes too. At first you see the entire landscape of opporutnities but with the help
of guided direction and focus you can hone in on the subject and key component of the image with the help
of the lens. I see the lens as a blinder of other distractions like the advice mentioned above of being alone
and going analog. Only with giving up some focus and detail of the many other components, can one truly focus in
and capture that main idea.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ApproximateAnalogy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feedback]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/feedback-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/feedback-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Guidance]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guidance</p>
<p>I think the word "Guidance" is an impactful way to marry two very important components
within the framwork of feedback outlined in Kirkwoods article, "How to give designers feedback they can actually use". These components would be "reinforcing" and "redirecting" feedback. Guidance encompasses these two terms far better than it would encompass "positive" and "negative" feedback Positive and negative are very black and white terms with no room for growth and interpretation that
guidance lives by. Through feedback following the ideals of guidance one can easily integrate
other best practices described in the article. For example, Kirkwood mentions that when giving redirecting feedback the ideal situation is a back and forth of clarifying and open ended questions where the team guides eachother to a solution rather than being told what exactly to do. This also
ties into one of the most vital parts of productive feedback which is fostering an environment of
ownership. Through guidance through both redirection and reinforcment the designer feels more agency
over their work as they were a central part of the feedback loop in this situations. When someone
is being talked at, it is easy to feel like a dispensible cog in the machine. This is so important for creative jobs like design as providing ones unique talents, experiences and perspectives is tantamount to the work experience, rather than just a set of hands who knows how to use a certain software.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.invisionapp.com/inside-design/give-designers-feedback/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.invisionapp.com/inside-design/give-designers-feedback/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>WordJournal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portfolio Design Sketch]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/portfolio-design-sketch</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/portfolio-design-sketch</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[https://blog.uxfol.io/ux-portfolio-examples/]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.uxfol.io/ux-portfolio-examples/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://blog.uxfol.io/ux-portfolio-examples/</a></p>
<p>Today I got inspired by Klaudia Simon and Ákos Izsák's article "23 Succesful
UX Portfolio Examples and a Guide for Creating Yours.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="riya portfolio sketch" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/riya-ui-portfolio-sketch-85e0484bc580b37b4e4b103ec315f885.png" width="500" height="329" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This article gave a wealth of valuable information from concrete steps to follow to create a succesful UX portfolio to learning by example by presenting cutting edge examples. I decided to try out this advice and
ideas myself through a quick figma mockup of a potential frontpage of my
UI/UX portfolio. I was very inspired by the minimalistic, brutalist UI styles that masterfully use whitespace and sans serif text for a sleek,
modern approach. I personally throught the examples could use more contrast so I decided use my favorite shade of saturated purple to embue my personality and add a high contrast pop against an off white background. I also made the background an off white yellow hue to better complement the purple accents. I have always been a fan of retro, typewriter like fonts
with a modern approach so I used fonts that best embody that! Another personal spin I implemented was the organized chaos of different sized image displays that lack order but fit toegther in the expanse of white space. I made sure to follow the advice of the article of using the
same style mockups through royalty free ui images and also making sure they are front and center on my home page. I also added the key navigation mentioned like home, resume, and contacts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>SketchInspo</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Project Process]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/final-project-process</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/final-project-process</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Design System]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Design System</p>
<iframe style="border:1px solid rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1)" width="800" height="450" src="https://embed.figma.com/design/UK9uUpAhDIBDZ92RVxjQA3/Final-Project-Design-System?node-id=0-1&amp;embed-host=share"></iframe>
<p>Mockups</p>
<iframe style="border:1px solid rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);" width="800" height="450" src="https://embed.figma.com/design/jRVpSZsTvUqHXvoQ7sIYMx/Final-Project-Design-System-(Copy)?node-id=0-1&amp;embed-host=share"></iframe>
<p>Protoype</p>
<iframe style="border:1px solid rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);" width="800" height="450" src="https://embed.figma.com/proto/vMADeAuVf2QUHi2hdHYOT4/Final-Project-Design-System-(Copy)-(Copy)?node-id=37-2&amp;node-type=canvas&amp;scaling=min-zoom&amp;content-scaling=fixed&amp;page-id=0%3A1&amp;starting-point-node-id=37%3A2&amp;show-proto-sidebar=1&amp;embed-host=share"></iframe>
<p>User Testing Changes</p>
<iframe style="border:1px solid rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);" width="800" height="450" src="https://embed.figma.com/design/vMADeAuVf2QUHi2hdHYOT4/Final-Project-Design-System-(Copy)-(Copy)?node-id=0-1&amp;embed-host=share"></iframe>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Navigating Values]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/navigating-values</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/navigating-values</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[To further identify my own  values I was inspired and decided to loosly]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To further identify my own  values I was inspired and decided to loosly
follow the excercise from Brené browns
book <i> Dare to Lead </i>.</p>
<p>The first step of this excercise is to identify the values
that we initially connect with.This is indicated by all the values which have
been highlighted in the image. The values highlighted purple indicate the values
under the main value Achievment, the values highlighted green fall under
Groth, and the blue ones embody Belonging.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="1st step valuess" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/1st-step-values-217d57d32890a4efe1854a91ed03e417.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After this I drilled down even further on what two
overarching values encapsulate the initial group
of values I selected.I ended up with:</p>
<p>"Authenticity": Achievement, Ambition, Initiative,
Personal Fulfillment, Belonging, Balance, Ethics
,Creativity, Curiosity, Humility, Independence,
Perseverance,Uniqueness</p>
<p>"Legacy"
Legacy,Pride,Recognition,Self-Expression, Loyalty, Learning, Inclusion,
Humor,Fun,Friendship,Fairness,Diversity,Dignity,Connection,Competence
,Making a Difference</p>
<p>Finally, I created two sentences to concisely communicate the
scope of these core two values and all the context from
other values to personalize it to my perspective.</p>
<p>Authenticity expresses the way I want to lead my decisions
and creative process in a manner that fully maximizes my abilities.</p>
<p>I value legacy in the sense  of the impact of my personhood on
those around me and in the value I am able to create or colloborate on
throughout time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finding Inspiration]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/finding-inspiration-excercise</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/finding-inspiration-excercise</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Finding Inspiration Through Art]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finding Inspiration Through Art</p>
<p>Passion Flowers and Hummingbirds by Martin Johnson Heade
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="passionflowers and hummingbirds image" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/passionflowers-hummingbirds-f1c8a7621c3fd864214c947d7f0f6fa5.jpeg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>A couple of yearsa ago I visited the Boston Museum of Fine Arts and found myself enamored by
several pieces. After some time I still find the piece “Passion Flowers and Hummingbirds” by the American artist Martin Johnson Heade to be the most compelling. The creation of this painting spanned from 1870-1883. One of the most fascinating parts regarding the history of this piece is how Heade was inspired by the revolutionary knowledge of Charles Darwin’s studies on evolution. He already had a fascination with hummingbirds since childhood and this was further exacerbated by Darwins example of hummingbird beak adaption for the purpose of fertilizing hummingbirds. During his trip to Central America he painted the interrelationship between flora and fauna he saw in Panama while also integrating spiritual elements of Christianity through nuances within the form of his paintings.</p>
<p>Art Analysis</p>
<p>Saturation
<a href="https://drawpaintacademy.com/color-saturation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://drawpaintacademy.com/color-saturation/</a></p>
<p>Heade masterfully uses saturation guide the viewers eye to the most important parts of the painting and set the mood. The passionflower are the intended focus of this painting and Heade drives this point home using a vibrant, highly saturated shade of red. The color context is important with this choice as the passionflowers are the most saturated hue present in this painting. If the vines and leaves adorning the flowers were the same level of saturation the pop the passionflowers give would get washed out and thus have less impact Atmospheric perspective is another component of this painting which means as an object recedes, it mirrors its surrounding appearance more. One component of this means that as an object is more in the background it tends to be less saturated and more dull which is clearly seen in the brush and fog in this painting. This is also a component of depth which will be discussed in the next section!</p>
<p>Depth
<a href="https://www.bbcmaestro.com/blog/creating-depth-in-art" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.bbcmaestro.com/blog/creating-depth-in-art</a></p>
<p>Creating depth in an artwork is achieved through choices that leverage the facets of color and how the human eye works. Despite this being a flat canvas the painting looks to be a snapshot of a bundle of flowers lost in an imposing, foggy jungle that goes as far as the eye can see. As previously mentioned atmospheric depth is one way to do this as objects in the background will be far more dull and desaturated. Another way this illusion of depth is refined is through detail and focus. This is best seen through how Heade painted the jungle brush. The brush that is seen at the bottom of the canvas has clear individual leaves where light hits the tops of them and underneath eacb leaf is shrouded in shadow. Going to the brush slightly above that, the shadows become more blurry and muted and the colors blend together more creating a lower resolution look which corresponds to being further away. These are all further driven home through value which will be discussed in the final section of contrast!</p>
<p>Contrast
<a href="https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/what-is-contrast-in-art-definition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/what-is-contrast-in-art-definition/</a></p>
<p>The final component that brings together this painting is contrast! Contrast is a fascinating feature of art due to manifesting in several different ways. The primary way is through complementary colors which are opposite colors on the color wheel. This is present in the painting through the vibrant red flowers and the muted green foliage. The next way is the contrast between dark and light or value. The passionflower closest to the hummingbirds has the brightest red colors even among the other flowers which indicates it is the first thing Heade wanted the viewer to look at. Not only does he use saturation to differentiate different elements in the painting, but the same objects as well. There is an also contrast present between the bright fog and the dark foliage. Lastly the size of the elements create contrast which is seen through the large, highly detailed flowers in the foreground and the much smaller foliage as the painting gets further away. These all work together to create depth and visual interest.</p>
<p>#You should take a photo or scan of your sketch and add it to your blog post. Then, describe your UI. What kind of device is it intended for (web, mobile, treadmill, etc.)? What is the page's topic (calendar app, news site, Starburst-themed casino machine, etc.)? What about the inspiration piece are you replicating in this sketch?
Finally, conclude your post with something insightful you learned through this process.
Go get inspired!</p>
<p>Inspiration Sketch</p>
<p>##Inspiration Sketch
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Inspiration Sketch" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/finding-inspo-sketch-80fcf988a6013853d278b22107e59a2e.jpeg" width="2398" height="1651" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The UI I sketched up is intended to be used on the web as some sort of application dealing with a users
music. I used the same color palettes as the art piece I chose and due to their complementary nature
I found it leaving a very crisp, refined but still creative look. To capture the depth exhihbited in the
work I chose I used a carosuel displaying each album where a user would swipe through and see the item of
focus come to the foreground and the others fade into the foreground.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Designs Systems]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Standardization]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Standardization</p>
<p>Standardization is at the crux of this weeks reading. Just as users of interfaces don't want to overthink things, so do designers working together on a team to create a product! This is why standardization is key which manifests in tools like style guides and content strategy. Content strategy focuses on edge cases which style guides may not cover. This includes features like which capitalization structure to use, a set standard of vocabulary for actions with many possible word choices, and localization for different languages and cultural conventions. Style guides are similar to documentation for software. They are an extensive packet of guidelines and components used in an interface. Everyone has that experience watching a phenomenal presentation but the legitimacy is brought down as it is clear different people worked on a different sections of the slide deck. Style guides circumvent this issue by working to achieve visual consistency and representative branding.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>WordJournal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Color 1 Podcast]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-1-podcast</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-1-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Podcast -  Color]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Podcast -  Color</p>
<p>In this podcast I ask my friend Fatima for the insight she can deliver on the world of
color through her expertise as an artist. We explore what different colors mean to us,
what components that make up a color are most important, and discuss how we use color
in our artistic process.</p>
<audio controls=""><source src="../static/color1-podcast.m4a" type="audio/m4a"><p>Your browser does not support the audio element.</p></audio>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Podcast</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Color Harmony Excercise]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Color Harmony UI Excercise]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>##Color Harmony UI Excercise</p>
<p>Today I will be embarking on a journey exploring different color harmonies impact on
an interface. I thought what better interface to experiment with than the color puzzle game
"I Love Hue"! I will first analyze and recreate the original palette of this interface and then spin up three different iterations of this interface with different harmonic color
combinations.</p>
<p>##Original Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue original interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-og-fcd648927d5d55d5553ea8e9130b3ea0.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>##Recreation of Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue recreated interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-recreation-2a89106366046b4d15afcd7479748280.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The original color scheme of the I love hue interface fits into the triad harmony, these
being the primary colors of yellow, red, and blue. This color scheme exemplifies simplicity and harmony. I think this was a very intelligent choice from the designers as primary colors
are the foundation of the game which tests users eye for colors and how each hue fits together.  As this is a relaxing low stakes puzzle game I think these muted colors work very well to not excite the mind too much and allow the player to relax and focus on the colors of the puzzle to solve.</p>
<p>##Achromatic Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue achromatic interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-achromatic-bea6166fe4aabf9fa9885aeb4f569d56.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The first color scheme I tried my hand at was an achromatic color scheme using
black and white and all the shades in between those colors. This was my favorite new
iteration by far. It stays true to the values of simplicity and ease on the mind.This sleek,
simple palette allows for the colors of the puzzle to truly shine and be the main focus of
the game. This also thematically fits well into the game similar to their primary triad
harmony.</p>
<p>##Anagolous Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue anagolous interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-anagolous-f15b8e261cadfe4c83a177c309d62096.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The next color harmony I tried was an analogous color palette. I used blue, blue green and
blue violet. I choose to use a blue analogous palette as blue evokes feeling of peace and
relaxation which fits the purpose of the game. I think this palette is very soothing to the
eye and mind, however it has more potential to clash based on the colors of the puzzle. I think the fact certain color puzzles will stand out and pop far more than others is a detriment to this design.</p>
<p>##Square Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue square interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-square-6d5091605dfc8310d62b652dbe5d2664.png" width="850" height="1836" class="img_ev3q">
The last color harmony I tried out is a square color harmony. I used red, green, purple
and yellow. I wasn't the biggest fan of this palette as it gave it a more childish, chaotic
look compared to the other choices. I think this would also clash with the palettes of
the puzzles potentially. I think this gives the energy of a more fast paced, energetic game
rather than the slow, meticilous process i love hue creates.</p>
<p>##Final Thoughts
Overall I think the original color scheme was the most effective for this game. It
was very purposeful and truly lives up to the name of the game by incorporating
all the primary colors. The point of the game is to get lost in the world of color
and relax and the triad harmony is a wonderful vessel to present this. The achromatic
palette is a close second due to the reasons I love the original palette so much.
It doesn't distract from the puzzle which is the central focus and creates a feeling
of peace and calmness.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colors 2]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Psychology of Color Through Television]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Psychology of Color Through Television</p>
<p>These sections dive into the psychology of color from the feelings each hue in the rainbow invoke to the lucrative market of understanding color trends for different customer segments. One of the most beautiful ways the psychology of color manifests is through film and television. This also is a very intuitive way to understand color theory and the impact of color as our brain subconsciously reacts to the creators choices. One of the best ways in our generation this was demonstrated was in the HBO series Euphoria. Each character has very deliberate colors that make up their wardrobe and this even changes as characters develop and transition. Maddie is a strong, independent, hard to read and confident character which is perfectly exemplified through her palette of rich purples. As purple is the color of royalty is also reflects her desire for upward social mobility. Cassie is often adorned in baby blues which mirror her highly sensitive, emotional personality. It also reflects her character traits of being a people pleaser and impulsive and to be on the nose the sadness and grief that surrounds her character. Kat's whole character arc is about developing confidence in herself and her body as a plus size women. This is beautifully demonstrated as she starts wearing the bold, dominating, and eye catching colors of red and black.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aesthetic Design]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds</p>
<p>The rule of thirds was a very important section of this reading . The rule of thirds is derived from another concept called "the golden ratio", which means we are drawn to images that have proportions following the golden ratio which for rectangles has the proportions of 1:1.618. The rule of thirds acts is a technique that all starts with superimposing a 3x3 grid onto the piece in question. The corners of the middle square are the "power points" which are the ideal areas to place your power points. This is a personal tangent but I thought for the longest time the rule of thirds meant that when you are adding the same design elements it is best to do it in groups of three for the most balance. My mom taught me this when she would create bouquets and it is a principle I always think about when creating artwork. I am curious if this abstraction of the official rule of thirds rule has any basis because it always felt like something that elevated my designs. Now I will paste some art pieces I have created and see how well they follow the rule of thirds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Aesthetic Design Analysis" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/aesthetic-design-analysis-bb44c1c1e4346a11fedc786526ae1135.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[example-blog-post]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 15:54:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>