<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>My UI Portfolio Blog</title>
        <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog</link>
        <description>My UI Portfolio Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 04:26:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[example-blog-post]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 04:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Designs Systems]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Brene brown list of 100 values]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>title: Designs Systems
slug: /design-systems
date: 2024-10-11T14:30:00Z
tags: [freeform]
---Brene brown list of 100 values</p>
<p>To further identify my own  values I was inspired and decided to loosly
follow the excercise from Brené browns
book <i> Dare to Lead </i>.</p>
<p>The first step of this excercise is to identify the values
that we initially connect with.This is indicated by all the values which have
been highlighted in the image. The values highlighted purple indicate the values
under the main value Achievment, the values highlighted green fall under
Groth, and the blue ones embody Belonging.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="1st step valuess" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/1st-step-values-217d57d32890a4efe1854a91ed03e417.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After this I drilled down even further on what two
overarching values encapsulate the initial group
of values I selected.I ended up with:</p>
<p>"Authenticity": Achievement, Ambition, Initiative,
Personal Fulfillment, Belonging, Balance, Ethics
,Creativity, Curiosity, Humility, Independence,
Perseverance,Uniqueness</p>
<p>"Legacy"
Legacy,Pride,Recognition,Self-Expression, Loyalty, Learning, Inclusion,
Humor,Fun,Friendship,Fairness,Diversity,Dignity,Connection,Competence
,Making a Difference</p>
<p>Finally, I created two sentences to concisely communicate the
scope of these core two values and all the context from
other values to personalize it to my perspective.</p>
<p>Authenticity expresses the way I want to lead my decisions
and creative process in a manner that fully maximizes my abilities.</p>
<p>I value legacy in the sense  of the impact of my personhood on
those around me and in the value I am able to create or colloborate on
throughout time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finding Inspiration]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/finding-inspiration-excercise</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/finding-inspiration-excercise</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Finding Inspiration Through Art]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>##Finding Inspiration Through Art</p>
<p>##Passion Flowers and Hummingbirds by Martin Johnson Heade
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="passionflowers and hummingbirds image" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/passionflowers-hummingbirds-f1c8a7621c3fd864214c947d7f0f6fa5.jpeg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>A couple of yearsa ago I visited the Boston Museum of Fine Arts and found myself enamored by
several pieces. After some time I still find the piece “Passion Flowers and Hummingbirds” by the American artist Martin Johnson Heade to be the most compelling. The creation of this painting spanned from 1870-1883. One of the most fascinating parts regarding the history of this piece is how Heade was inspired by the revolutionary knowledge of Charles Darwin’s studies on evolution. He already had a fascination with hummingbirds since childhood and this was further exacerbated by Darwins example of hummingbird beak adaption for the purpose of fertilizing hummingbirds. During his trip to Central America he painted the interrelationship between flora and fauna he saw in Panama while also integrating spiritual elements of Christianity through nuances within the form of his paintings.</p>
<p>##Art Analysis</p>
<p>##Saturation
<a href="https://drawpaintacademy.com/color-saturation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://drawpaintacademy.com/color-saturation/</a></p>
<p>Heade masterfully uses saturation guide the viewers eye to the most important parts of the painting and set the mood. The passionflower are the intended focus of this painting and Heade drives this point home using a vibrant, highly saturated shade of red. The color context is important with this choice as the passionflowers are the most saturated hue present in this painting. If the vines and leaves adorning the flowers were the same level of saturation the pop the passionflowers give would get washed out and thus have less impact Atmospheric perspective is another component of this painting which means as an object recedes, it mirrors its surrounding appearance more. One component of this means that as an object is more in the background it tends to be less saturated and more dull which is clearly seen in the brush and fog in this painting. This is also a component of depth which will be discussed in the next section!</p>
<p>##Depth
<a href="https://www.bbcmaestro.com/blog/creating-depth-in-art" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.bbcmaestro.com/blog/creating-depth-in-art</a></p>
<p>Creating depth in an artwork is achieved through choices that leverage the facets of color and how the human eye works. Despite this being a flat canvas the painting looks to be a snapshot of a bundle of flowers lost in an imposing, foggy jungle that goes as far as the eye can see. As previously mentioned atmospheric depth is one way to do this as objects in the background will be far more dull and desaturated. Another way this illusion of depth is refined is through detail and focus. This is best seen through how Heade painted the jungle brush. The brush that is seen at the bottom of the canvas has clear individual leaves where light hits the tops of them and underneath eacb leaf is shrouded in shadow. Going to the brush slightly above that, the shadows become more blurry and muted and the colors blend together more creating a lower resolution look which corresponds to being further away. These are all further driven home through value which will be discussed in the final section of contrast!</p>
<p>##Contrast
<a href="https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/what-is-contrast-in-art-definition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/what-is-contrast-in-art-definition/</a></p>
<p>The final component that brings together this painting is contrast! Contrast is a fascinating feature of art due to manifesting in several different ways. The primary way is through complementary colors which are opposite colors on the color wheel. This is present in the painting through the vibrant red flowers and the muted green foliage. The next way is the contrast between dark and light or value. The passionflower closest to the hummingbirds has the brightest red colors even among the other flowers which indicates it is the first thing Heade wanted the viewer to look at. Not only does he use saturation to differentiate different elements in the painting, but the same objects as well. There is an also contrast present between the bright fog and the dark foliage. Lastly the size of the elements create contrast which is seen through the large, highly detailed flowers in the foreground and the much smaller foliage as the painting gets further away. These all work together to create depth and visual interest.</p>
<p>#You should take a photo or scan of your sketch and add it to your blog post. Then, describe your UI. What kind of device is it intended for (web, mobile, treadmill, etc.)? What is the page's topic (calendar app, news site, Starburst-themed casino machine, etc.)? What about the inspiration piece are you replicating in this sketch?
Finally, conclude your post with something insightful you learned through this process.
Go get inspired!</p>
<p>##Inspiration Sketch</p>
<p>The UI I sketched up is intended to be used on the web.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Designs Systems]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/design-systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Standardization]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>title: Designs Systems
slug: /design-systems
date: 2024-10-11T14:30:00Z
tags: [freeform]
---Brene brown list of 100 values</p>
<p>To further identify my own  values I was inspired and decided to loosly
follow the excercise from Brené browns
book <i> Dare to Lead </i>.</p>
<p>The first step of this excercise is to identify the values
that we initially connect with.This is indicated by all the values which have
been highlighted in the image. The values highlighted purple indicate the values
under the main value Achievment, the values highlighted green fall under
Groth, and the blue ones embody Belonging.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="1st step valuess" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/1st-step-values-217d57d32890a4efe1854a91ed03e417.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After this I drilled down even further on what two
overarching values encapsulate the initial group
of values I selected.I ended up with:</p>
<p>"Authenticity": Achievement, Ambition, Initiative,
Personal Fulfillment, Belonging, Balance, Ethics
,Creativity, Curiosity, Humility, Independence,
Perseverance,Uniqueness</p>
<p>"Legacy"
Legacy,Pride,Recognition,Self-Expression, Loyalty, Learning, Inclusion,
Humor,Fun,Friendship,Fairness,Diversity,Dignity,Connection,Competence
,Making a Difference</p>
<p>Finally, I created two sentences to concisely communicate the
scope of these core two values and all the context from
other values to personalize it to my perspective.</p>
<p>Authenticity expresses the way I want to lead my decisions
and creative process in a manner that fully maximizes my abilities.</p>
<p>I value legacy in the sense  of the impact of my personhood on
those around me and in the value I am able to create or colloborate on
throughout time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>WordJournal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Color 1 Podcast]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-1-podcast</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-1-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Podcast -  Color]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Podcast -  Color</p>
<p>In this podcast I ask my friend Fatima for the insight she can deliver on the world of
color through her expertise as an artist. We explore what different colors mean to us,
what components that make up a color are most important, and discuss how we use color
in our artistic process.</p>
<audio controls=""><source src="../static/color1-podcast.m4a" type="audio/m4a"><p>Your browser does not support the audio element.</p></audio>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Podcast</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Color Harmony Excercise]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Color Harmony UI Excercise]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>##Color Harmony UI Excercise</p>
<p>Today I will be embarking on a journey exploring different color harmonies impact on
an interface. I thought what better interface to experiment with than the color puzzle game
"I Love Hue"! I will first analyze and recreate the original palette of this interface and then spin up three different iterations of this interface with different harmonic color
combinations.</p>
<p>##Original Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue original interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-og-fcd648927d5d55d5553ea8e9130b3ea0.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>##Recreation of Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue recreated interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-recreation-2a89106366046b4d15afcd7479748280.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The original color scheme of the I love hue interface fits into the triad harmony, these
being the primary colors of yellow, red, and blue. This color scheme exemplifies simplicity and harmony. I think this was a very intelligent choice from the designers as primary colors
are the foundation of the game which tests users eye for colors and how each hue fits together.  As this is a relaxing low stakes puzzle game I think these muted colors work very well to not excite the mind too much and allow the player to relax and focus on the colors of the puzzle to solve.</p>
<p>##Achromatic Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue achromatic interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-achromatic-bea6166fe4aabf9fa9885aeb4f569d56.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The first color scheme I tried my hand at was an achromatic color scheme using
black and white and all the shades in between those colors. This was my favorite new
iteration by far. It stays true to the values of simplicity and ease on the mind.This sleek,
simple palette allows for the colors of the puzzle to truly shine and be the main focus of
the game. This also thematically fits well into the game similar to their primary triad
harmony.</p>
<p>##Anagolous Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue anagolous interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-anagolous-f15b8e261cadfe4c83a177c309d62096.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The next color harmony I tried was an analogous color palette. I used blue, blue green and
blue violet. I choose to use a blue analogous palette as blue evokes feeling of peace and
relaxation which fits the purpose of the game. I think this palette is very soothing to the
eye and mind, however it has more potential to clash based on the colors of the puzzle. I think the fact certain color puzzles will stand out and pop far more than others is a detriment to this design.</p>
<p>##Square Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue square interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-square-6d5091605dfc8310d62b652dbe5d2664.png" width="850" height="1836" class="img_ev3q">
The last color harmony I tried out is a square color harmony. I used red, green, purple
and yellow. I wasn't the biggest fan of this palette as it gave it a more childish, chaotic
look compared to the other choices. I think this would also clash with the palettes of
the puzzles potentially. I think this gives the energy of a more fast paced, energetic game
rather than the slow, meticilous process i love hue creates.</p>
<p>##Final Thoughts
Overall I think the original color scheme was the most effective for this game. It
was very purposeful and truly lives up to the name of the game by incorporating
all the primary colors. The point of the game is to get lost in the world of color
and relax and the triad harmony is a wonderful vessel to present this. The achromatic
palette is a close second due to the reasons I love the original palette so much.
It doesn't distract from the puzzle which is the central focus and creates a feeling
of peace and calmness.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colors 2]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Psychology of Color Through Television]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Psychology of Color Through Television</p>
<p>These sections dive into the psychology of color from the feelings each hue in the rainbow invoke to the lucrative market of understanding color trends for different customer segments. One of the most beautiful ways the psychology of color manifests is through film and television. This also is a very intuitive way to understand color theory and the impact of color as our brain subconsciously reacts to the creators choices. One of the best ways in our generation this was demonstrated was in the HBO series Euphoria. Each character has very deliberate colors that make up their wardrobe and this even changes as characters develop and transition. Maddie is a strong, independent, hard to read and confident character which is perfectly exemplified through her palette of rich purples. As purple is the color of royalty is also reflects her desire for upward social mobility. Cassie is often adorned in baby blues which mirror her highly sensitive, emotional personality. It also reflects her character traits of being a people pleaser and impulsive and to be on the nose the sadness and grief that surrounds her character. Kat's whole character arc is about developing confidence in herself and her body as a plus size women. This is beautifully demonstrated as she starts wearing the bold, dominating, and eye catching colors of red and black.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aesthetic Design]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds</p>
<p>The rule of thirds was a very important section of this reading . The rule of thirds is derived from another concept called "the golden ratio", which means we are drawn to images that have proportions following the golden ratio which for rectangles has the proportions of 1:1.618. The rule of thirds acts is a technique that all starts with superimposing a 3x3 grid onto the piece in question. The corners of the middle square are the "power points" which are the ideal areas to place your power points. This is a personal tangent but I thought for the longest time the rule of thirds meant that when you are adding the same design elements it is best to do it in groups of three for the most balance. My mom taught me this when she would create bouquets and it is a principle I always think about when creating artwork. I am curious if this abstraction of the official rule of thirds rule has any basis because it always felt like something that elevated my designs. Now I will paste some art pieces I have created and see how well they follow the rule of thirds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Aesthetic Design Analysis" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/aesthetic-design-analysis-bb44c1c1e4346a11fedc786526ae1135.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>