<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>My UI Portfolio Blog</title>
        <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog</link>
        <description>My UI Portfolio Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Color Harmony Excercise]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/color-harmony-excercise</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Color Harmony UI Excercise]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>##Color Harmony UI Excercise</p>
<p>Today I will be embarking on a journey exploring different color harmonies impact on
an interface. I thought what better interface to experiment with than the color puzzle game
"I Love Hue"! I will first analyze and recreate the original palette of this interface and then spin up three different iterations of this interface with different harmonic color
combinations.</p>
<p>##Original Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue original interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-og-fcd648927d5d55d5553ea8e9130b3ea0.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>##Recreation of Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue recreated interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-recreation-2a89106366046b4d15afcd7479748280.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The original color scheme of the I love hue interface fits into the triad harmony, these
being the primary colors of yellow, red, and blue. This color scheme exemplifies simplicity and harmony. I think this was a very intelligent choice from the designers as primary colors
are the foundation of the game which tests users eye for colors and how each hue fits together.  As this is a relaxing low stakes puzzle game I think these muted colors work very well to not excite the mind too much and allow the player to relax and focus on the colors of the puzzle to solve.</p>
<p>##Achromatic Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue achromatic interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-achromatic-bea6166fe4aabf9fa9885aeb4f569d56.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The first color scheme I tried my hand at was an achromatic color scheme using
black and white and all the shades in between those colors. This was my favorite new
iteration by far. It stays true to the values of simplicity and ease on the mind.This sleek,
simple palette allows for the colors of the puzzle to truly shine and be the main focus of
the game. This also thematically fits well into the game similar to their primary triad
harmony.</p>
<p>##Anagolous Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue anagolous interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-anagolous-f15b8e261cadfe4c83a177c309d62096.png" width="850" height="1810" class="img_ev3q">
The next color harmony I tried was an analogous color palette. I used blue, blue green and
blue violet. I choose to use a blue analogous palette as blue evokes feeling of peace and
relaxation which fits the purpose of the game. I think this palette is very soothing to the
eye and mind, however it has more potential to clash based on the colors of the puzzle. I think the fact certain color puzzles will stand out and pop far more than others is a detriment to this design.</p>
<p>##Square Interface
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="ilovehue square interface" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/ilovehue-square-6d5091605dfc8310d62b652dbe5d2664.png" width="850" height="1836" class="img_ev3q">
The last color harmony I tried out is a square color harmony. I used red, green, purple
and yellow. I wasn't the biggest fan of this palette as it gave it a more childish, chaotic
look compared to the other choices. I think this would also clash with the palettes of
the puzzles potentially. I think this gives the energy of a more fast paced, energetic game
rather than the slow, meticilous process i love hue creates.</p>
<p>##Final Thoughts
Overall I think the original color scheme was the most effective for this game. It
was very purposeful and truly lives up to the name of the game by incorporating
all the primary colors. The point of the game is to get lost in the world of color
and relax and the triad harmony is a wonderful vessel to present this. The achromatic
palette is a close second due to the reasons I love the original palette so much.
It doesn't distract from the puzzle which is the central focus and creates a feeling
of peace and calmness.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colors 2]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/colors-2-blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Psychology of Color Through Television]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Psychology of Color Through Television</p>
<p>These sections dive into the psychology of color from the feelings each hue in the rainbow invoke to the lucrative market of understanding color trends for different customer segments. One of the most beautiful ways the psychology of color manifests is through film and television. This also is a very intuitive way to understand color theory and the impact of color as our brain subconsciously reacts to the creators choices. One of the best ways in our generation this was demonstrated was in the HBO series Euphoria. Each character has very deliberate colors that make up their wardrobe and this even changes as characters develop and transition. Maddie is a strong, independent, hard to read and confident character which is perfectly exemplified through her palette of rich purples. As purple is the color of royalty is also reflects her desire for upward social mobility. Cassie is often adorned in baby blues which mirror her highly sensitive, emotional personality. It also reflects her character traits of being a people pleaser and impulsive and to be on the nose the sadness and grief that surrounds her character. Kat's whole character arc is about developing confidence in herself and her body as a plus size women. This is beautifully demonstrated as she starts wearing the bold, dominating, and eye catching colors of red and black.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aesthetic Design]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/aesthetic-design-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Art Analysis- Rule of Thirds</p>
<p>The rule of thirds was a very important section of this reading . The rule of thirds is derived from another concept called "the golden ratio", which means we are drawn to images that have proportions following the golden ratio which for rectangles has the proportions of 1:1.618. The rule of thirds acts is a technique that all starts with superimposing a 3x3 grid onto the piece in question. The corners of the middle square are the "power points" which are the ideal areas to place your power points. This is a personal tangent but I thought for the longest time the rule of thirds meant that when you are adding the same design elements it is best to do it in groups of three for the most balance. My mom taught me this when she would create bouquets and it is a principle I always think about when creating artwork. I am curious if this abstraction of the official rule of thirds rule has any basis because it always felt like something that elevated my designs. Now I will paste some art pieces I have created and see how well they follow the rule of thirds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Aesthetic Design Analysis" src="https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/assets/images/aesthetic-design-analysis-bb44c1c1e4346a11fedc786526ae1135.jpg" width="2244" height="2904" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Example Blog Post]]></title>
            <link>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</link>
            <guid>https://riyakannapareddy.github.io/riya-ui-portfolio/blog/example-blog-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>FreeForm</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>